Icon. Genius. Rebel
Dancer is a documentary film directed by Steven Cantor.
Sergei Polunin is a breathtaking ballet talent who questions his existence and
his commitment to dance just as he is about to become a legend.
Himself, played by Sergei Polunin.
Himself, played by Jade Hale-Christofi.
The Dancer (French: La Danseuse) is a 2016 biographical historical drama film about dancer Loie Fuller, directed by Stéphanie Di Giusto from a
screenplay she co-wrote with Sarah Thiebaud and Thomas Bidegain, based on the novel Loïe Fuller: Danseuse de la Belle Époque by Giovanni Lista.
The film stars Soko, Gaspard Ulliel, Mélanie Thierry, Lily-Rose Depp,
François Damiens, Louis-Do de Lencquesaing and Denis Ménochet.
The film is a co-production between France, Belgium and Czech Republic.
The film made its world premiere in the Un Certain Regard
section of the 2016 Cannes Film Festival.
It was released theatrically on 28 September 2016 in France by Wild Bunch and in Belgium by
Lumière, and on 19 January 2017 in the Czech Republic by Film Distribution Artcam.
The film explores themes of dance, ballet dancer, ballet.